Declan Greenhalgh

http://www.decln.com Email: dec@decln.com

Who I am

I am a software developer who works at Tesco in the Online Search area, powering the ability to find products across the business. I have previously worked for Rightmove, in the Data Services Team, ION Trading (in the FX space), and NatWest Markets (formerly RBS M&IB, within the Futures space). I have worked on both large-scale re-engineering projects, as well as smaller bespoke applications. Whilst I mainly work in Java 8 & 11, I am equally keen on working with Python and .NET technologies.

I have followed an atypical route into software development/management, having come from a psychology background prior to my computer science education. This background complements my skills in software engineering, with my main interests being in organisational capabilities, Agile practices and development processes - all contributing to regular delivery of high value change.

I aim to continue growing in a technical application management role, but still want to preserve my technical skills. Potential career paths that interest me include enterprise architecture and developer management, but I am open to gaining a range of experiences.

Employment

Tesco Plc.

Software Development Engineer II (April '20 - Present)

- Continuation of backend-focused work, utilising Java 8 and 11.
- Specifically worked on more infrastructure-related projects, utilising Kubernetes in AWS and Azure environments.
- > Supporting legacy data ingestion applications using Apache Camel and Elasticsearch.
- > Spearheaded integrations with new Enterprise APIs, and worked directly with product teams to introduce new functionality on the Tesco site.

Rightmove Plc.

Developer (October '18 - April '20)

- > Backend-focused developer working on applications supporting property science.
- ➤ Working on Java versions 7, 8 and 11 developing Microservices.
- Creating Python 3 microservices for application of machine learning models, using Flask APIs and Sklearn.
- > Introduction of Elasticsearch to support more data-heavy projects across the business, as well as minor use of Kafka for ingestion and production of events.
- > Some front-end development in AngularJS and React.
- Utilisation of Spring Frameworks (inc. Spring Boot) and Docker.
- > Expanded testing knowledge using Cucumber and Selenium for functional testing, and Pact for Consumer Driven Contracts.

ION Trading Ltd.

Developer (February '18 - September '18)

- ➤ Worked on a large-scale FX trade management re-engineering project.
- Primarily used Java 8.
- Use of ATDD (Robot Framework) and mocking frameworks (Mockito).
- > Utilised dependency injection frameworks (Guice), and Spring Hibernate.
- > Focused on the delivery of a post-trade solution with an emphasis on service-oriented architecture.
- > Gained experience working with larger Agile teams using the LeSS framework.

NatWest Markets (Royal Bank of Scotland Group)

Application Manager / Developer - Associate (September '17 - February '18)

- > A continuation of the below role, in a permanent capacity.
- > An increased focus on application design, project management, stakeholder management, and providing services as the application SME.
- Worked on the implementation of various MiFID II project deliverables.

MThree Consulting Ltd / NatWest Markets

Developer (September '15 - September '17)

- Worked primarily in an application management/developer role in the Futures Technology space.
- ➤ Day-to-day was working on the in-house Futures Execution & Clearing Order Management System that handles execution and allocation routing between the full F2B stack. Have previously worked on a major transformation project due to a 3rd-party vendor switch, working on the entire lifecycle in an agile environment.
- > Have been responsible for the implementation of CMMI within my application.
- > Technologies used include Java 7, FIX Protocol, Oracle SQL, Unix, TIBCO EMS, IBM MQ and a variety of agile tools.

University of Kent Information Services

Assistant Support Desk Supervisor (September 2014 – August 2015)

- > Role included supervisory & SME aspects.
- > Required to manage the University IT services at the weekend and out of hours.

IT and Library Support Desk Assistant (April 2013 – September 2014)

- Customer-facing helpdesk role helping with technical issues.
- > Helped develop my abilities to deal with a range of customers, communicating with relevant colleagues and maintaining a presentable, professional work environment.

Education

MSc. Computer Science. University of Kent. 2014 - 2015

Obtained a Master's degree in a programme covering a wide range of computing concepts, including: Java-based Object Oriented Programming, Web-Based Information Systems, Logic Programming, Machine Learning and Systems Architecture.

BSc. (Hons.) Psychology and Sociology, University of Kent, 2011-2014

Obtained a 2:1. Undertook two research projects in my final year, including a technical-based electroencephalography study in Psychology.

Lancaster Royal Grammar School, 2005-2011

Obtained an 'A' grade in History, and 'B' grades in Chemistry, French, Drama and General Studies A-Levels. Gained 12 GCSEs A*-C, including English Literature (A*), English Language (A) and Maths (A).

Professional Affiliations:

- > British Psychological Society, with a title of MBPsS. Part of the Division of Occupational Psychology.
- British Computing Society, with the title of MBCS. Member of additional Specialist Groups including Software Process Improvement Network, Software Practice Advancement, Agile Methods, Financial Services and Advanced Programming.

Additional Information & Interests

- > I enjoy playing the piano in my spare time.
- > Treasurer and committee member of the University's trampolining team for two years.
- > British Gymnastics' qualified judge, and have judged at national competitions to an elite level.
- Received Green Colours from Kent Sport for the administrative service I provided to the club.